注：Secret Informant意思是秘密线人，但是内容都是美食
Hong Kong maybe a world-class destination.
香港是一个众所周知的旅游胜地
注：中文字幕和英文字幕均为官方字幕，未经修改
But the best food isn't only found in fancy restaurants.
不过好吃的东西不仅仅只在高级餐厅里
Like any major international city,
和许多国际大都市一样
注：旁白是techlinked的Riley，本视频上传于20180907
Some of the tastest dishes in Hong Kong are best enjoyed out on the streets with friends.
很多好吃的小食必须和朋友逛街时在街道上找到
And...while Leo and I are close,
尽管 Leo 和我关系不错
two people is not a party.
但是两个人开不了派对
So we got Joyce and Phyllis,
所以我们找到了 Joyce 和 Phyllis
The people behind @hkfoodlover on Instagram,
两位是IG频道 @hkfoodlover 的主持人
To show us where there is to eat on the streets of Mong Kok,
来给我们介绍在旺角能找到什么好吃的小食
One of the busiest shopping areas in the city.
旺角是香港最繁忙的购物区之一
And we weren't quite prepared for what we were going to eat first.
我们对接下来要吃的东西并没有做好足够的心理准备
Hi, guys, guess where we are.
嗨 大家好 猜猜我们现在在哪儿
We are in Mong Kok.
我们在旺角
One of the busiest streets in Hong Kong.
这里是香港最繁忙的街道之一
So what are we doing here on the busiest street in Hong Kong?
我们来这条繁忙的街道上做什么呢
Let's go eat.
我们去吃东西吧
What's the one right behind us? Which one is this all about?
在我们背后这家是什么店呢
What's the one right behind us? Which one is this about?
And it's having some kind of organs.
他们的特色是动物内脏
Are you gonna try?
你们一定要试试
Organs?
你是说动物内脏
Some organs.
好吃的内脏哟
Like this instrument?
还是那个乐器（organ也是能翻译成管风琴）
There is a huge line up. That looks very popular.
队伍排的好长 看起来好受欢迎
It's kind of the most popular shop, I would say, in this street.
肥姐小食店可以说是这条街上最受欢迎的一家店了
Let's get over there. Let's cross the street.
我们过马路吧
We are having octopus. We are having kidney...
我们准备吃章鱼 准备吃胗干
...other reproductive organs.
还有其他一些动物生殖器官
I didn't even know those were eatable.
这些东西能吃么
Everything is edible.
什么东西都能吃
So...this is the octopus.
这是章鱼
And this is the female organ which we mentioned just now.
这是我们刚才提到的动物生殖器官
And this is the kidney.
最后这个是胗干
You wanna try?
你们要试试么
I mean ye...yeah.
好啊
You have to try.
你们必须试试
You go first.
你先咬一口
Me first?
我先哦
It's like just on the edge of crunchy.
这口感离脆就差一点点
It's not quite crunchy, but it's like...
并没有很脆
It's like in between chewy and crunchy.
可以说在有嚼劲和脆之间
The flavour is pretty much of that like...meat.
味道的话基本上就是肉味
The hot mustard and the...dark sause is very nice.
加上芥末酱和这个黑黑酱调味很好
Sweet sauce.
这黑黑酱是甜酱
Kidney...kidney's up.
吃胗干吼
This is a kidney?!
这是胗干么
If you just fed me this with my eyes closed, I would've thought this was a vegetable.
如果我闭着眼睛吃的话会以为这是蔬菜
I've never had octopus. I've had squid.
我从来没吃过章鱼 我只吃过鱿鱼
You're gonna love it.
你会喜欢的
It like cooked in some sort of sweet sause.
吃起来这个是和什么甜味酱一起烧的
Like it's kinda...that's why it's in orange.
这酱料是表面呈橘黄色的原因么
A lot of mustard.
很多芥末酱哦
It went like right up my nose.
那个是芥末酱 芥末味冲到鼻子里了
Oh god.
哦 天哪
It was just kind of like MUSTARD.
一开始芥末味很强烈
And then it kind of like the mustard kinds went away.
接着慢慢消散
And the kind of a...fishy taste came in, but it's like good.
然后能尝到淡淡的鱼腥味 很好味
Then you guys should try this.
你们应该尝尝这个
Which I don't like.
我个人不是太喜欢
You don't like this.
你不喜欢这个哦
Among the three.
是这三个里面比较不喜欢的
This is a female organ of some kind.
这是动物生殖器的一部分
Very inner part.
是体内的一部分
I don't think I like it all that much.
我也不是太喜欢这个味道
It's got this after taste, but it's always there.
是这个余味持续不断
I can...I can't really describe the after taste.
形容不上来这个余味是什么感觉
It's kind of like semi bitter...and semi salty.
有点苦苦的也有点咸咸的
The texture was great.
口感倒是不错
It was just like a sausage casing.
有点像是脆脆的香肠外皮
You bite it, and it kinda like pops.
咬下去会轻轻爆开这个样子
I don't know...I just...It wasn't for me.
我不觉得这道是我的菜
Will you recommend to any of your friends?
你会向你的朋友推荐这道小食么
The third one...the third one.
第三种哦
I think it's definitely worth trying.
确实值得尝试一下
This translates pretty well over the...over to the west.
这个很好理解
Baked goods and bakery.
面包和糕点
This is pancake. It's called siu beng.
这些是烧饼
It's like very chewy kinda texture.
口感很有嚼劲
Is it similar like mochi?
这个类似于麻薯么
Kinda...custard...peanuts
类似 有奶黄馅 花生酱馅
And then red bean, and then original flavour which is nothing inside.
还有红豆馅 原味就是实心饼
It's chicken biscuits. Gai zai beng.
这是鸡仔饼
You can try.
你可以试试
There is no chicken in it.
里面可没有鸡肉哦
Just named after a chicken.
这只是取名叫鸡仔饼而已
For this shop is really famous for the...for the siu beng.
这家店以他们的烧饼出名
So is that what we are getting right now?
我们是要买几个烧饼么
Yeah, we can try...try this one first.
当然 我们可以先试试这个
Dig in.
开吃咯
I got like no red bean.
我都没吃到红豆馅
Oh no, i think you did, but it's like...seals it off.
有哦 看起来是咬下去都挤在一起了
They baked really good. A big bite.
这些饼做的很好吃
Yeah, so like...chewy.
看这个好有弹性
There is it...there is like an elasticity to it.
这饼做的超有弹性的
More chewy than mochi.
这比麻薯更有嚼劲
Local people all we always like to go to bakery shop.
这里的本地人都很喜欢这样的饼店
And like for breakfast, for tea time, some snacks.
这些饼能当早餐吃 喝茶的时候吃 下午当点心吃
We just have Tim Hortons.
我们那儿有 Tim Hortons
This is like a Timbit of Hong Kong.
这饼就好像是香港的 Timbits
Cost comperison, a Timbit of Hong Kong.
这饼和 Timbits 比起来价格差不多
This is chicken biscuit that doesn't have any chicken in it.
这是没有鸡肉在里面的鸡仔饼
Yes.
没错
Why is it called a chicken biscuit?
那为什么要叫鸡仔饼呢
Because it's made with pork fat.
因为这是猪油做的
It kinda looks like it could be chicken?
是因为这看起来比较像鸡块么
Yeah, yeah. Chicken nugget.
不觉得么 外形像炸鸡块
What is in there?
里面有啥东西哦
What's on the inside?
里面这是啥
It's uh...pork fat.
有猪油
It's giving off a natural saltiness.
这尝起来有一种天然的咸味
The actual pastry around it kinda just like it's very crumbly.
周围包裹的一层是松松的酥饼
It's like you bite into this little biscuit and then there is bacon on the inside almost.
感觉就好像是咬下一口饼干发现里面包着培根
It's not bacon.
里面包的不是培根
But it's like pork fat kinda taste.
不过这猪油让它尝起来像是培根
The biscuit is kinda like crumbly, so when it mixed with the pork fat, it kinda becomes like a paste.
外面包裹的糕点和里面的猪油拌在一起的时候会呈糊状
It's a tough paste, like a toffee kind of.
这种黏黏的口感像是在嚼太妃糖
I don't know if I'd like that.
我不确定我是不是喜欢这口感哦
It's not bad.
味道是不错啦
But I'm like "would I get it again?" I don't know.
我不确定我会再回来买这个
It's like Timbits as well. Where if you eat more than three...you are kinda just like...
这和 Timbits 一样 如果一下子吃三个以上
You will get diabetes.
你会得糖尿病
You will get diabetes...immediately.
没错 会立刻得糖尿病
You should get one of this, go home, and share.
可以买一袋回家和家人一起分享
You just like having it in it feeling like "oh god, I've eaten too much. Like this...I need to stop."
会感觉 噢 天哪 我不能再吃了 吃太多了
I feel greasy and kind of...
这太多太腻了
Well, thank you so much for showing us around.
非常感谢带我们逛街
We are gonna do this again with you guys, right?
我们还会在见的是吧
Yeah, sure.
当然啦
More to come with Joyce and Phyllis of @hkfoodlover,
接下来会有更多和 Joyce 还有 Phyllis 一起拍摄的内容
And more to come from Secret Informant.
更多内容由 Secret Informant 为您呈现
See you soon.
下回见啦
Thanks for watching this video, which is produced by Tattle.
感谢您观看这集由 Tattle 制作的影片
If you don't know, Tattle is a brand new platform connecting savvy locals with curious explorers.
Tattle 是一个全新的帮助探险者连接本地向导的网络平台
Check us out on social media.
来我们的社交媒体上看看
And sign up for our newsletter at the link in the description.
点击下面的链接订阅 Tattle 的每周电子期刊
Big thanks to Joyce and Phyllis for showing us around Mong Kok.
感谢 Joyce 和 Phyllis 带我们逛旺角
And be sure to check out their Instagram page @hkfoodlover.
快去他们的IG频道 @hkfoodlover 看看吧
See you next time.
下回见咯